Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Dan Seymour Papers, 1951-1974 RL.00747
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Corporate Administration Series, 1955-1973, undated (bulk 1956-1965).
  - Corporate Administration: Office Files Subseries, 1955-1971 (bulk 1960s).
    - Speeches:
      - Porter, Arthur A., "The New Dimension of Radio," 1957, Mar. 25 (Box 20)
      - Strouse, Norman H.:
        - "Modern Advertising: American Marvel or World Force?," 1961, May 8 (Box 20)
        - "Responsibility - Keynote of the Sixties," 1961, Nov. 29;"Measuring the Value of Advertising in Our Society," 1962, June 21 (Box 20)
    - Thomas, Franklyn R., "Imagineering: Vital Buy-Product of Business," 1964 (Box 21)
    - Wilson, Edward G., "Talk by Edward G. Wilson to selected members of Sydney Office Staff," 1962, Oct. 31 (Box 21)
    - (JWT) Stock, 1964 (Box 21)
    - Testing commercials ( Schwerin Research Corp.), 1963 (Box 21)
    - Clippings:
      - 1958-1964 (Box 21)
      - (JWT) Presidency, 1964 (Box 21)
  - J. Walter Thompson Company Offices Subseries, 1960-1964, undated
    Includes correspondence, memoranda, reports, tables, minutes, and printed material. See also oversize materials. Arranged alphabetically by the name of the office, then chronologically therein.
    - Chicago, 1961-1964, undated, 2 folders (Box 21)
    - Detroit, 1962-1964 (Box 21)
    - London, 1961-1962 (Box 21)
    - Los Angeles, 1963-1964 (Box 21)
    - Manila, 1960-1962 (Box 21)
    - San Francisco, 1961-1962 (Box 21)
  - Reports Subseries, 1956-1966, undated
    Includes reports by the J. Walter Thompson Company. Arranged alphabetically by title.
    - "Account Group Procedures," 1961 (Box 21)
    - "Advertising Budget Requirements," 1956-1964 (Box 21)
    - "Advertising Planning, Creative Department, and Campaign Evaluation at J. Walter Thompson," 1965 (Box 21)
    - "Advertising Spending Level Experiment/Calendar Year 1963, 1962 (Box 21)
    - "How Research Can Improve Advertising for J. Walter Thompson Clients," 1959-1963 (Box 22)
    - "An Improvement Program for J. Walter Thompson," 1961[?] (Box 22)
    - "International Service Slide Presentation," [1961] (Box 22)
    - "An Introduction to Marketing Research at J. Walter Thompson," 1960[?] (Box 22)
    - "Manager of Creative Services," [1965?] (Box 22)
    - "Marketing Semantics," 1965 (Box 22)
    - "Measured Advertising Results," 1963 (Box 22)
    - "Network Program Development," 1965-1966 (Box 22)
    - "The New Revolution in Distribution and Its Significance for National Advertisers," 1961 (Box 22)
    - "Notes for Executive Committee and Board of Directors Meeting," 1965 (Box 22)
    - "Outline of a Process that Should Make for Effective Marketing Communications," 1963 (Box 22)
    - "The Packaging Industry," 1961 (Box 22)
    - "Philosophy or Point of View on 'Public Reputation' Advertising," undated (Box 22)
    - "Principles of Advertising," 1963 (Box 22)
    - "Production Department and Personnel Evaluation," 1963 (Box 22)
    - "Professionalism in Advertising Agency Practise [sic]," 1964 (Box 23)
    - "Program for Guidance Research," JWT Research Department, [1963?] (Box 23)
    - "Programme for Advertising Research," 1964 (Box 23)
    - "Programmed Advertising," 1964 (Box 23)
    - "Project Youth," 1960s (Box 23)
    - "Seminar and Development Program," undated (Box 23)
    - "Some Facts About the J. Walter Thompson Company," 1960 (Box 23)
    - "Story of Six Retailers, Sequel to Revolution in Retailing, Marketing-Merchandising Department," 1962 (Box 23)
    - "A Strategy for the Future," 1963 (Box 23)
    - Symposium on the Negro Market," by JWT Marketing Department, 1963 (Box 23)
    - "Thompson's Tomato Fresh Tomato Juice, A New Product Presentation Advertising Workshop," 1964 (Box 23)
    - "U.S. Textile Industry," by JWT Market Research Department, 1962? (Box 23)
  - Miscellaneous Subseries, 1956-1971, undated
    Includes correspondence, reprints, printed material, and clippings. Arranged by subject.
    - "Buff Papers" from Norman H. Strouse: Excerpts of published literature selected and circulated by Strouse to JWT executives, 1964 (Box 24)
    - Constructive Publicity about the J. Walter Thompson Co. (a clipping collage), 1960 (Box 24)
  - Miscellaneous Subseries
    - Hayes, Arthur Hull, "Suppose They'd Never Invented Radio," 1956, Nov. 13
      - Sandage, C. H., "The Next Step: A Philosophical Foundation for Advertising," 1960s; Universal Broadcasting System, "This is UBS," undated (Box 24)
    - Servan-Schreiber, Jean-Jacques:
      - 1970-1971 (Box 24)
      - Forcer le Destin, 1970 (Box 24)
  - Clients Series, 1951-1970, undated (bulk 1955-1964).
    Forms the largest series, including correspondence, memoranda, notes, reports, call reports, advertisements, and printed material. See also oversize materials. Arranged alphabetically by client names. Clients with extensive materials are further arranged into general, chronological files; then alphabetically in topical files; then alphabetically by product names; and then alphabetically by titles of television shows. Topical files often contain reports.
    - Alberto-Culver Company, 1961-1970, 3 folders (Box 24)
    - Aluminium, Ltd., 1955-1962 (Box 24)
    - American Electric Power, 1964 (Box 24)
    - American Home Products, 1963-1964 (Box 24)
    - American Petroleum Institute, 1962 (Box 24)
    - Atlantis Sales Corporation, 1957 (Box 24)
    - Brillo Manufacturing Company, 1955 (Box 24)
    - Chesebrough-Pond's, 1955-1964 (Box 25)
    - Chun King Corporation, 1956-1964 (Box 25)
    - CIBA Pharmaceutical Products, undated (Box 25)
    - Continental Airlines, 1964 (Box 25)
    - Cutex, 1961 (Box 25)
    - Dean Witter, 1963-1964 (Box 25)
    - Eastman Kodak, 1955-1958, 7 folders (Box 25)
    - Eastman Kodak: (Box 26)
    - Chronological files:
      - 1960-1964, 2 folders (Box 26)
    - Topical files:
      - Broadcast Exploitation Service Adapted to the Needs of Eastman Kodak, 1957, Oct. (Box 26)
      - Call Reports, 1956-1958, 2 folders (Box 26)
      - Commercials, scripts, properties, writers and credits, 1955-1962 (Box 26)
      - Daytime Programs, Columbia Broadcasting System, 1957 (Box 26)
      - International Sales and Advertising Area managers visit to JWT, 1958 (Box 26)
      - Nielsen Ratings, 1956-1958 (Box 26)
      - "Profile of Camera Owners and Users," 1954-1956 (Box 26)
      - Recommendation: 1962Advertising Recommendations for International Department, 1961 (Box 26)
    - Eastman Kodak: (Box 27)
    - Topical files:
      - Recommendation:
        - Continued Network Television Sponsorship of " Ed Sullivan Show," " Ozzie and Harriet," 1960-1961 (Box 27)
        - Network Participation Plan, 1962, Feb. 15 (Box 27)
        - A Suggestion for Special Kodak TV Programming, 1961, Feb. 14 (Box 27)
      - Screen Gems, 1956 (Box 27)
      - Speech by Gerald B. Zornow, Vice-President, "Pictures Make the Business," to MPDFA Convention, 1960 (Box 27)
      - Television Presentation outline, 1955? (Box 27)
      - TV Advertising Budgets [" Walt Disney's Wonderful World of Color"], 1962 (Box 27)
      - United States Golf Association National Open Tournament, 1956 (Box 27)
    - Television shows:
      - "Beat the Clock," 1957-1958 (Box 27)
      - " Ed Sullivan Show," 1957-1958, 2 folders (Box 27)
      - " Ozzie and Harriet," 1956, Apr.-Sept. (Box 27)
    - Eastman Kodak: (Box 28)
    - Television shows:
      - "Ozzie and Harriet": 1956-1958, 3 folders (Box 28)
      - Legal, 1956-1968 (Box 28)
      - Publicity, 1956-1958 (Box 28)
      - Scripts, 1956 (Box 28)
    - "Screen Directors Playhouse," 1955-1956, Oct., 2 folders (Box 28)
    - Eastman Kodak: (Box 29)
    - Television shows:
      - "Screen Directors Playhouse":
        - Hal Roach Studios:
          - 1955-1956 (Box 29)
          - Invoices, 1956 (Box 29)
        - Production Status reports, 1955-1956 (Box 29)
        - Publicity, 1955-1956 (Box 29)
        - Scripts, 1955-1956 (Box 29)
        - Weekly reports and story status reports, 1955-1956 (Box 29)
      - "Walt Disney's Wonderful World of Color," 1961-1962 (Box 29)
    - Clippings, 1956-1964 (Box 29)
    - Elgin National Watch Company, 1956-1957 (Box 30)
    - Firestone Tire and Rubber Company, 1956 (Box 30)
    - Florist Telegraph Delivery Association, 1956 (Box 30)
    - Ford Motor Company: (Box 30)
    - Chronological files:
      - 1956-1961, 9 folders (Box 30)
    - Ford Motor Company: (Box 31)
    - Chronological files:
      - 1962-1964, 5 folders (Box 31)
    - Topical files:
      - Field representatives meetings, 1958-1964 (Box 31)
      - Ford Dealer Association, 1957-1964, undated (Box 31)
      - National Football League, 1962-1964 (Box 31)
      - Penetration, 1964-1965 (Box 31)
    - Ford Motor Company: (Box 32)
    - Topical files:
      - Profit/Loss, penetration, 1962 (Box 32)
      - Radio, 1956-1958 (Box 32)
      - Recommendations, 1956-1962, 5 folders (Box 32)
      - Strategy presentation: 1965passenger Car, 1964, Mar. (Box 32)
    - Ford Motor Company: (Box 33)
    - Topical files:
      - Television planning, 1956-1963 (Box 33)
      - Tractor division, 1962-1964 (Box 33)
      - Trip to United States, Europe and Asia, 1957 (Box 33)
    - Television shows:
      - "Buckskin," 1958 (Box 33)
      - "Ensign O'Toole," 1962 (Box 33)
      - "The FBI, Code 98," 1962 (Box 33)
      - "Ford Road," 1958 (Box 33)
      - "The Ford Show," 1956-1958, 2 folders (Box 33)
      - "Ford Star Jubilee," 1955-1956, July (Box 33)
    - Ford Motor Company: (Box 34)
    - Television shows:
      - "Ford Star Jubilee," 1956, Aug.-1958, undated (Box 34)
      - "Ford Theatre," 1956-1957, 2 folders (Box 34)
      - "Hazel," 1962-1964, 2 folders (Box 34)
      - Kelly and Garland Specials, 1962 (Box 34)
      - "Living Ones," 1962 (Box 34)
      - " Lucille Ball - Desi Arnaz Hour Show," 1957-1958 (Box 34)
      - "Startime," 1962 (Box 34)
      - "Sunday Sports Spectacular," 1962 (Box 34)
      - "Suspicion," 1957-1958 (Box 34)
      - "Wagon Train," 1958 (Box 34)
      - "Zane Grey Theatre," 1956-1958 (Box 34)
    - Foremost Dairies, 1956 (Box 34)
    - French's, 1957 (Box 34)
    - General Tire, 1956-1957 (Box 35)
    - Good Humor Corporation: Advertising recommendations, 1964, Feb. 18 (Box 35)
    - Gu-H: Gulf Oil, 1951-1955; Helene Curtis Industries, 1962; H.F. Richie Co.\Scotts Emulsion, 1956 (Box 35)
    - Institute of Life Insurance, 1962-1964 (Box 35)
    - International Business Machines Corporation, "IBM, A Business and Its Beliefs," 1964 (Box 35)
    - Johnson Motors, 1956-1957 (Box 35)
    - Jos. Schlitz Brewing Company:
      - 1956-1957 (Box 35)
      - Call reports, 1956, Mar.-Sept., 3 folders (Box 35)
    - Jos. Schlitz Brewing Company: (Box 36)
      - Call reports, 1956, Oct.-1957, 2 folders (Box 36)
      - "Arthur Godfrey," 1955-1956 (Box 36)
    - Kodak: see Eastman Kodak Company (Box 36)
    - Kraft Foods Company: (Box 36)
    - Chronological files:
      - 1956, Feb.-1958, 7 folders (Box 36)
    - Kraft Foods Company: (Box 37)
    - Chronological files:
      - 1961-1964, 2 folders (Box 37)
    - Television shows:
      - "Kraft Music Hall," Milton Berle, 1958-1964 (Box 37)
      - "Kraft Mystery Theatre," 1958-1962, undated (Box 37)
      - "Kraft Suspense Theater," 1964 (Box 37)
      - "Kraft Television Theatre," 1956-1958, 3 folders (Box 37)
    - Kraft Foods Company: (Box 38)
    - Television shows:
      - "Perry Como Kraft Music Hall," 1962 (Box 38)
      - "Perry Como Show," 1964 (Box 38)
    - Kraft Foods Company and Sealtest, "Bat Masterson," 1957-1958 (Box 38)
    - Lever Brothers Company: (Box 38)
    - Chronological files:
      - 1955-1964(3 folders) (Box 38)
    - Topical files:
      - Board of Directors meeting, 1955 (Box 38)
      - Brand Review, 1964, June 18 (Box 38)
      - Columbia Broadcasting System ( CBS) and National Broadcasting Company ( NBC) Overall Discount Status, 1958 (Box 38)
    - Unilever Conference paper, 1962, Sept.-1963, Feb.(2 folders) (Box 38)
    - Lever Brothers Company: (Box 39)
    - Topical files:
      - Unilever Conference paper, undated (Box 39)
    - Product files:
      - Handy Andy, 1964 (Box 39)
      - Lux Liquid, 1955-1964 (Box 39)
      - Stripe Toothpaste, 1956-1958 (Box 39)
    - Television shows:
      - " Eve Arden Show," 1957-1958 (Box 39)
      - "Father Knows Best," 1958 (Box 39)
      - " Garry Moore Show," 1955-1956 (Box 39)
      - "Haggis Baggis," 1958 (Box 39)
      - "Have Gun Will Travel," 1957-1958 (Box 39)
      - "The Jackie Gleason Show," 1958 (Box 39)
      - "Keep Talking," 1958 (Box 39)
      - "Lux-Schlitz Playhouse," 1957-1958 (Box 39)
      - "Lux Shows:" Call reports, 1958 (Box 39)
      - "The Lux Show: Rosemary Clooney," 1957-1958 (Box 39)
      - "Lux Video Theatre":
        - 1956-1958 (Box 39)
        - Gordon MacRae, 1956 (Box 39)
      - "On Trial," 1956 (Box 39)
      - "The Price is Right," 1958 (Box 39)
      - "Sir Lancelot," 1956 (Box 39)
    - Libby, McNeill and Libby, 1957-1964 (Box 39)
    - Liebmann Breweries, 1961-1963, 2 folders (Box 40)
    - Liggett and Myers Tobacco Company: (Box 40)
    - Chronological files:
      - 1956-1964, 3 folders (Box 40)
    - Topical files:
      - "The Continuing Study of Advertising Impact and Consumer Attitudes for the Liggett and Myers Tobacco Company: A Report on Phase I," 1961, Dec. (Box 40)
      - "The Continuing Study of Cigarette Smoking, Brand Preferences, and Brand Switching," 1964 (Box 40)
      - " LandM Cigarettes Recommended Strategy and Advertising Plan, October-December 1961; "LandM Cigarettes Proposed Marketing Strategy and Advertising Plan, 1962 1961, Nov. (Box 40)
    - Management luncheons, 1964 (Box 40)
    - Management meetings, 1962 (Box 40)
    - Liggett and Myers Tobacco Company: (Box 41)
    - Topical files:
      - Research Department, Albro Martin, 1964 (Box 41)
      - Responsibility Reporting System: Norman Sondak reports, 1964 (Box 41)
      - Shipments, 1964 (Box 41)
    - Product files:
      - Chesterfield:
        - 1961-1962 (Box 41)
        - Cigarettes Marketing Plans, 1961-1962 (Box 41)
      - Devon, 1964 (Box 41)
      - Duke Filter Cigarettes, 1961-1962 (Box 41)
      - LandM Filters, 1964 (Box 41)
      - Lark, 1964 (Box 41)
    - Television shows:
      - " Andy Williams Show," 1962 (Box 41)
      - "Checkmate," 1961 (Box 41)
      - "English O'Toole," 1962 (Box 41)
      - "Fair Exchange," 1962 (Box 41)
      - "Follow the Sun," 1961 (Box 41)
      - "The Tonight Show," 1962 (Box 41)
      - "Twilight Zone," 1961 (Box 41)
      - "The Virginians," 1962 (Box 41)
      - "87th Precinct," 1961 (Box 41)
    - McGraw-Edison Voicewriter Division, 1964 (Box 41)
    - Mentholatum Company, 1962 (Box 41)
    - Mobil Oil (International), 1961-1962 (Box 41)
    - Morris Plan Company, 1964 (Box 41)
    - New Holland Machine Company, 1964 (Box 41)
    - New York Central, 1956 (Box 41)
    - New York World's Fair, 1962-1964 (Box 41)
    - Northeast Airlines, 1962 (Box 41)
    - Oneida, 1956 (Box 41)
    - Oscar Mayer: Chicago, 1964 (Box 41)
    - Owens-Illinois, 1955-1956 (Box 42)
    - Pan American World Airways, 1956-1964 (Box 42)
    - Pharmacraft, 1956-1957 (Box 42)
    - Philco, 1956 (Box 42)
    - Phillips Petroleum Company:
      - 1962-1964(2 folders) (Box 42)
      - Beer Concentrate presentation, 1964 (Box 42)
    - Quaker Oats Company, 1957-1964(2 folders) (Box 42)
    - Radio Corporation of America ( RCA):
      - 1964 (Box 42)
      - Advertising presentation, 1964, July 1 (Box 42)
    - Reader's Digest, 1962-1964 (Box 42)
    - Russel M. Seeds Company, 1957 (Box 42)
    - S: Scripto, 1957; Sweets Co. of America, 1956 (Box 42)
    - Sabroso Coffee: New Product Presentation Training Program, 1963 (Box 42)
    - Safeway, 1962-1963 (Box 42)
    - Schlitz: see Jos. Schlitz Brewing Company (Box 42)
    - Scott Paper Company, 1956-1957 (Box 42)
    - Scott Paper Company: (Box 43)
      - 1962, Nov.-1964(2 folders) (Box 43)
      - "Father Knows Best," 1956-1957 (Box 43)
      - "Gisele MacKenzie," 1957 (Box 43)
      - Reports, 1957-1960 (Box 43)
    - Sea World, 1964 (Box 43)
    - Seven-Up Company, 1956-1963(3 folders) (Box 43)
    - Singer Company:
      - 1963-1964(2 folders) (Box 43)
      - Corporate Advertising Idea Book, 1964, June (Box 43)
      - "Advertising Objectives, Creative Strategy and Media Recommendations For 1964," 1964 (Box 43)
    - Standard Brands: (Box 44)
      - 1956-1964 (Box 44)
      - Weigl meeting material, 1964 (Box 44)
      - "A Blind and Identified Product Test of Instant Chase and Sanborn and Instant Maxwell House," 1964, July (Box 44)
    - Swift TV, 1954 (Box 44)
    - United States Marine Corps., 1963-1964 (Box 44)
    - United States Lines, 1963-1964 (Box 44)
    - United States Playing Card Company, 1956-1964 (Box 44)
    - W. F. Young, 1963-1964 (Box 44)
    - Walt Disney Productions, 1964-1965 (Box 44)
    - Warner-Lambert Pharmaceutical Company:
      - 1962-1964(3 folders) (Box 44)
      - Listerine Antiseptic, 1962-1964 (Box 44)
      - Product X Presentation, 1963 (Box 44)
      - Pro-phy-lac-tic Brush Company, 1962-1963 (Box 44)
    - Weco Products Company, 1957 (Box 44)
    - Westminster Paper Company, 1963 (Box 44)
- Professional Organizations and Activities Series, 1956-1971.
  Includes correspondence, reports, and printed materials. Arranged alphabetically by name of organization, then chronologically therein.
  - Academy of Television Arts and Sciences, 1961 (Box 45)
  - American Association of Advertising Agencies: Committee work, 1956-1957 (Box 45)
  - Boy's Clubs of America, 1970 (Box 45)
  - Marketing Science Institute, 1962-1965(6 folders) (Box 45)
  - Marketing Science Institute: Membership Conference, 1965 (Box 46)
  - Puerto Rico: Ad hoc Advisory Group on the Presidential Vote, 1971 (Box 46)
  - Veterans Hospital Radio and Television (Bedside Network), 1963-1965(2 folders) (Box 46)
- Miscellaneous Series, 1953-1974.
  Includes calendars; correspondence; memoranda; legal documents; financial documents and propositions, including a script of a play titled "Rashamon"; and reports. See also oversize materials. Arranged alphabetically and chronologically therein.
  - Calendar, 1956 (Box 46)
  - Calendars, 1957-1960(1 folder, 4 vols.) (Box 47)
  - Calendars, 1961-1965(3 folders, 6 vols.) (Box 48)
  - Calendars, 1966-1974(4 folders, 2 vols.) (Box 49)
  - Investments:
    - 1952, 1963 (Box 49)
    - "Rashomon" by Fay and Michael Kanin, 1958 (Box 49)
  - Address book (Box 50)
  - Young and Rubicam:
    - The Borden Co., undated (Box 50)
    - Clients, 1952-1959 (Box 50)
    - Correspondence, 1953, Apr.(2 folders) (Box 50)
    - Financial, 1950-1955 (Box 50)
- Oversize Materials
  - Radio-Television Department Series
    - Programming Subseries
      - Consumer Purchase Panel TV Study: Households reached by selected television programs, 1955, Nov. (Box 51)
      - Agents, scripts, studios, and stations, 1965, Sept.-1957 (Box 51)
  - Corporate Administration
    - Office Files Subseries
      - Review Board, Scott Paper Co.\Confidets, 1964 (Box 51)
      - Speech: Franklyn R. Thomas, "Imagineering: Vital Buy-Product of Business," 1964 (Box 51)
      - House advertisements, 1956-1962 (Box 51)
    - J. Walter Thompson Company Offices Subseries
      - London, 1962 (Box 51)
      - San Francisco, 1961 (Box 51)
  - Clients Series
    - Eastman Kodak: Share of Audience by Show Date for " Ed Sullivan Show" and Steve Allen's show, 1957-1958 (Box 51)
    - Ford Motor Company:
      - "Ford Star Jubilee," 1956,undated (Box 51)
      - Clippings, 1962-1964,undated (Box 51)
    - Lever Brothers Company: Handy Andy, 1964, May (Box 51)
    - Lever Brothers Company: "Lux Video Theater," Competitive Advertisement, 1965 (Box 51)
  - Miscellaneous Series
    - Calendars, 1973-1974, 2 folders (Box 51)